Norman Vincent Peale Papers
Norman Vincent Peale Papers
- II. Subject files
  - D: Radio files
    - Radio correspondence
      - Radio correspondence, 1943; 1944 (Box II:D:8)
      - Radio correspondence, 1945-1946 (Box II:D:9)
      - Radio correspondence, A-K, 1947 (Box II:D:9)
      - Radio correspondence, L-Z, 1947 (Box II:D:10)
      - Radio correspondence, 1948-1949 (Box II:D:10)
      - Radio correspondence, 1950 (Box II:D:11)
      - Radio correspondence, A-J, 1951 (Box II:D:11)
      - Radio correspondence, K-Z, 1951 (Box II:D:12)
      - Radio correspondence, A-L, 1952 (Box II:D:12)
      - Radio correspondence, M-Z, 1952 (Box II:D:13)
      - Radio correspondence, 1953
        - A-B (Box II:D:13)
        - C-H (Box II:D:14)
        - H-M (Box II:D:15)
        - N-S (Box II:D:16)
        - S-Z (Box II:D:17)
      - Radio correspondence, 1954
        - A (Box II:D:17)
        - B-C (Box II:D:18)
        - D-G (Box II:D:19)
        - H-K (Box II:D:20)
        - L-O (Box II:D:21)
        - P-S (Box II:D:22)
        - T-Z, unidentifiable (Box II:D:23)
      - Radio correspondence, 1955; arranged by subject
        - Alcoholics
          - Engaged to Known Alcoholics (Box II:D:23)
          - Husbands - Emphasis on Divorce, Finances (Box II:D:23)
          - Husbands - Wives not Wanting to Help (Box II:D:23)
          - Letters from Family (not Wife) (Box II:D:24)
          - Repentant Husbands (Box II:D:24)
          - Social Drinking (Box II:D:24)
          - Women Alcoholics (Box II:D:24)
        - Business and Finance, wills (Box II:D:24)
        - Children
          - Adopted or Foster (Box II:D:24)
          - Problems relating to Boys, Girls (Box II:D:24)
          - Retarded or Defective (Box II:D:24)
          - Serious Personality or Mental Trouble (Box II:D:24)
          - Sex Troubles (Box II:D:24)
          - Shy (Box II:D:25)
          - Grown and General (Box II:D:25)
          - General (Box II:D:25)
          - Parents, Grandparents Having Trouble (Box II:D:25)
        - Criticisms (Box II:D:25)
        - Divorce
          - Young Couples (Box II:D:25)
          - Questions (Box II:D:25)
          - Elderly Couple, Husband wants Divorce (Box II:D:25)
          - Elderly Couple, Wife wants Divorce (Box II:D:26)
          - Wanted for Various Reasons (Box II:D:26)
          - Feel Guilty Because of Divorce - Sin? (Box II:D:26)
        - Domestic
          - Finances - Property Settlement in Second Marriage (Box II:D:26)
          - Lonely - Wives, Husbands (Box II:D:26)
          - Nagging Troubles (Box II:D:26)
          - Sex (Box II:D:26)
        - Extra Marital Relations
          - General (Box II:D:26)
          - Pre-marital, Unwed mothers (Box II:D:27)
        - Family
          - Brothers and Sisters (Box II:D:27)
          - Duty to Parents (Box II:D:27)
          - Misc. (Box II:D:27)
        - Grief (Box II:D:27)
        - Health (Box II:D:27)
        - Health (Box II:D:28)
        - Infidelity
          - Last Fling, Elderly (Box II:D:28)
          - of Husband (Box II:D:28)
          - of Wife (Box II:D:28)
        - In-Law Trouble (Box II:D:28)
        - Love Problems
          - Middle Aged or Over (Box II:D:29)
          - Lonely Hearts (Box II:D:29)
          - Young (Box II:D:29)
        - Marriage Difficulties
          - Not Reached Divorce (Box II:D:29)
          - Marriage (Box II:D:29)
          - Marriage (Box II:D:30)
        - Misc. I (Box II:D:30)
        - Misc. II
          - Messy Sex Relations (Box II:D:30)
          - Rambling, Incoherent (Box II:D:31)
          - Requests for Copies of Radio Talks (Box II:D:31)
          - Racial Difficulties (Box II:D:31)
          - Mixed Creeds (Box II:D:31)
          - Statements (Box II:D:31)
        - Neighbors - Gossip (Box II:D:31)
        - Old age problems (Box II:D:31)
        - Personal Appearance (Box II:D:32)
        - Personality
          - Fear (Box II:D:32)
          - General (Box II:D:32)
          - Inferiority
            - Self-Conscious (Box II:D:33)
            - Mental Illness (Box II:D:33)
            - Worry - Anxiety (Box II:D:33)
        - Program Comments (Box II:D:33)
        - Program Comments (Box II:D:34)
        - Religious Creed and Church (Box II:D:34)
        - Religious Creed and Church (Box II:D:35)
        - Response to Radio Questions and Answers (Box II:D:35)
        - Requests for Themes (Box II:D:35)
        - Spouses
          - Unpleasant Personal Characteristics of Husbands (Box II:D:35)
          - Jealous Husbands (Box II:D:35)
          - Cruel, Abusive, Domineering Husbands (Box II:D:35)
          - Irresponsible, Shiftless Husbands (Box II:D:35)
          - Indifferent, Inattentive Husbands (Box II:D:35)
          - Disagreeable, Bad Tempered, Moody husbands (Box II:D:35)
          - Jealous, Discontented, Errant Wives (Box II:D:35)
          - Misc. Husbands (Box II:D:35)
          - Flirtatious, Philandering Husbands (Box II:D:35)
        - Youth
          - Children (Box II:D:36)
          - Teenagers (Box II:D:36)
          - Older, Misc. (Box II:D:36)
        - Alphabetically by Sender
          - Answered, A-H (Box II:D:36)
          - Answered, I-Z (Box II:D:37)
          - Unanswered, A-C (Box II:D:38)
          - Unanswered, C-G (Box II:D:39)
          - Unanswered, G-K (Box II:D:40)
          - Unanswered, L-N (Box II:D:41)
          - Unanswered, O-S (Box II:D:42)
          - Unanswered, T-Z (Box II:D:43)
      - Radio correspondence, 1956
        - Unanswered, A-F (Box II:D:44)
        - Unanswered, G-Q (Box II:D:45)
        - Unanswered, R-Z (Box II:D:46)
      - Radio correspondence, 1957
        - Unanswered, A-B (Box II:D:46)
        - Unanswered, C-T (Box II:D:47)
        - Unanswered, U-Z, unidentifiable (Box II:D:48)
        - Correspondence answered by Mrs. Graham (Box II:D:48)
        - Expense Account (Box II:D:48)
        - Office Correspondence (Box II:D:48)
        - Office - Mail Requests for N.V.P. Broadcasts (Box II:D:48)
        - Office Notes (Box II:D:48)
        - Office - Record of Mail Received and Sent at NBC (Box II:D:48)
        - Prayers, 1946-1947 Season (Box II:D:48)
        - Prayers, 1947-1949 Season (Box II:D:49)
        - Prayers, 1965, Jan. 17 (Box II:D:49)
        - Programs
          - 1943-1950, 1952 (Box II:D:49)
          - Lists of Illustrations "Art of Living", 1950-1953 (Box II:D:49)
          - Lists of Topics "Art of Living", 1954 (Box II:D:49)
        - Promotion, 1955-1959 (Box II:D:49)
        - Radio Questions used on the N.V.P. Show
          - 1955, Jan. 3, 10, 17, 24 (Box II:D:50)
          - 1955, Feb. 7, 14, 21, 28 (Box II:D:50)
          - 1955, Mar. 7, 14-18 (Box II:D:50)
          - 1955, Mar. 21, 28 (Box II:D:51)
          - 1955, Apr. 4-8, 11, 18, 25 (Box II:D:51)
          - 1955, May 2, 9, 16, 23 (Box II:D:51)
          - 1955, May 23, 30 (Box II:D:52)
          - 1955, Jun. 6, 13, 20, 27 (Box II:D:52)
          - 1955, Jul. 4, 11, 18, 25 (Box II:D:52)
          - 1955, Aug. 1, 8, 15, 22, 29 (Box II:D:53)
          - 1955, Sep. 5, 12, 19, 26 (Box II:D:53)
          - 1955, Oct. 3, 10, 17, 24, 31 (Box II:D:53)
          - 1955, Nov. 7, 14, 21, 28 (Box II:D:54)
          - 1955, Dec. 5, 12, 19, 26 (Box II:D:54)
        - Questions - Possible Selection for N.V.P. Show
          - 1955, Jan 11-Jun 24 (Box II:D:55)
          - 1955, Jun 30 - Nov. 30 (Box II:D:56)
        - Questions
          - Children (Box II:D:56)
          - Edited (Box II:D:56)
          - Unedited (Box II:D:56)
          - Marriage Difficulties (Box II:D:56)
          - New Booklet of N.B.C. Questions (Box II:D:57)
          - Personality - Inferiority, insecurity (Box II:D:57)
          - Rejected (Box II:D:57)
          - Submitted, Oct, Nov. (Box II:D:57)
          - Submitted by Miss Van Buren, July 5 - Nov. 29 (Box II:D:57)
          - Submitted by Rose Weiss (Box II:D:57)
        - Radio Sermons: Art of Living
          - 1938 (Box II:D:58)
          - 1940, Mar.7 - Sep.28 (Box II:D:58)
          - 1941, Apr.4 - Jun.28 (Box II:D:58)
          - 1941, Jul.5 - Sep.27 (Box II:D:58)
          - 1942, Jun.6 - Sep.26 (Box II:D:58)
          - 1942, Jul.4 - Sep.26 (Box II:D:58)
          - 1943, Feb 27 - Sep 22 (Box II:D:59)
          - 1944, Jun 3 - Sep 30 (Box II:D:59)
          - Month and Day Not Indicated (Box II:D:59)
          - 1945, Jun 2-Sep 29 (Box II:D:60)
          - 1946, Jun 1-Sep 28 (Box II:D:60)
          - 1947, May 3-Sep 27 (Box II:D:60)
          - 1948, Jun 5-Sep 25 (Box II:D:60)
          - 1949, Jun 4-Sep 24 (Box II:D:61)
          - 1950, Jun 4-Dec 31 (Box II:D:61)
          - 1951, Jan 7-Dec 30 (Box II:D:62)
          - 1952, Jan 6-Apr 6 (Box II:D:62)
          - 1952, Apr 13-Dec 28 (Box II:D:63)
          - 1953, Jan 11-Dec 27 (Box II:D:63)
          - 1954, Sep 5-Dec 26 (Box II:D:64)
          - 1955, Jan 2-Dec 25 (Box II:D:64)
          - 1956, Jan 1-Dec 30 (Box II:D:64)
          - 1957, Jan 6-Mar 31 (Box II:D:64)
          - 1957, Oct 13-Dec 29 (Box II:D:65)
          - 1958, Jan 5-Dec 28 (Box II:D:65)
          - 1959 (Box II:D:65)
          - 1960-1961 (Box II:D:65)
          - 1962 (Box II:D:66)
        - Radio Sermons: Faith in Our Time, 1945, Oct 17-Nov 28 (Box II:D:66)
        - Radio Sermons: Radio Chapel, 1945, Dec 9-30; 1946, Oct 6-27 (Box II:D:66)
        - Special sermons, 1954; Easter Seal Message (Box II:D:66)
        - WSYR (Syracuse, New York) sermons
          - 1929, Feb-Nov (Box II:D:66)
          - 1930, Jan-May (Box II:D:67)
          - 1930, May-Nov (Box II:D:67)
          - 1931 (Box II:D:67)
          - 1932, Jan-Mar (Box II:D:67)
          - No Date (Box II:D:67)
        - Other Sermons
          - 1942 Jan 3-Nov 29 (Box II:D:67)
          - 1942 Dec 6-27 (Box II:D:68)
          - 1943 Jan 24-Dec 26 (Box II:D:68)
          - 1944 Jan 16-Apr 2 (Box II:D:68)
          - 1944 Sep 17-Dec 10 (Box II:D:68)
          - 1945 Jan 7-14, Mar 5-18 (Box II:D:68)
          - 1945 Apr 1-Nov 25 (Box II:D:69)
          - 1945 Dec 2-30 (Box II:D:70)
          - 1946 Jan 6-Mar 31 (Box II:D:70)
          - 1946 Apr 7-Oct 27 (Box II:D:71)
          - 1946 Nov 3-Dec 31 (Box II:D:72)
          - 1947 Jan 5-Apr 27 (Box II:D:72)
          - 1947 May 4-Dec 21 (Box II:D:73)
          - 1948 Jan 4-Feb 22 (Box II:D:73)
          - 1948 Mar 7-Dec 26 (Box II:D:74)
          - 1949 Jan 2-Feb 20 (Box II:D:74)
          - 1949 Feb 27- Oct 16 (Box II:D:75)
          - 1951 Mar 4-Jun 10 (Box II:D:76)
          - 1952 Jan 27-Dec 28 (Box II:D:76)
          - 1953 Feb 18-Dec 13 (Box II:D:76)
          - 1954 Jan 3-Feb 28 (Box II:D:76)
          - 1954 Mar 7-Dec 30 (Box II:D:77)
          - 1955 Jan 23-Dec 25 (Box II:D:77)
          - 1956 Jan 1-Jun 3 (Box II:D:77)
          - 1956 Sep 17-Dec 30 (Box II:D:78)
          - 1957 Feb 24 (Box II:D:78)
          - 1957 Mar 8-Oct 27 (Box II:D:78)
          - 1957 Nov 3-Dec 29 (Box II:D:79)
          - 1958 Jan 5-Oct 26 (Box II:D:79)
          - 1958 Nov 2-Dec 28 (Box II:D:80)
          - 1959 Jan 4-Dec 27 (Box II:D:80)
          - 1960 Jan 3-Dec 25 (Box II:D:81)
          - 1961 Jan 1-Jun 11 (Box II:D:81)
          - 1961 Jul (Box II:D:82)
          - 1961 Sep 17-Dec 31 (Box II:D:82)
          - 1962 Jan 7-Dec 30 (Box II:D:82)
          - 1965 Jan 17 (Box II:D:83)
          - Undated (Box II:D:83)
          - Sermons from the book The Art of Living, and not useable, 1939; 1953 (Box II:D:83)
        - Sermon Discs
          - 1942 May 17-31 (Box II:D:83)
          - 1942 Sep 20-Dec 31 (Box II:D:83)
          - 1943 Jan 3-Feb 28 (Box II:D:83)
          - 1943 Mar 7-Oct 31 (Box II:D:84)
          - 1943 Nov 7-Dec 31 (Box II:D:85)
          - 1944 Jan 2-Apr 30 (Box II:D:85)
          - 1944 May 7-Dec 31 (Box II:D:86)
          - 1945 Jan 7-Feb 28 (Box II:D:86)
          - 1945 Mar 4-Dec 30 (Box II:D:87)
          - 1946 Jan 6-Oct 27 (Box II:D:88)
          - 1946 Nov 3-Dec 31 (Box II:D:89)
          - 1951 Nov 11 (Box II:D:89)
          - 1952 Oct 4 (Box II:D:89)
          - 1952 Dec 21-28 (Box II:D:89)
          - 1953 Mar 29-May 10 (Box II:D:89)
          - 1956 Jan 1-Jun 3 (Box II:D:89)
          - 1956 Sep 21-Oct 26 (Box II:D:89)
          - 1956 Sep 16- Dec 30 (Box II:D:90)
          - 1957 May 19-Oct 6 (Box II:D:90)
          - 1958 Sep 21-Oct 26 (Box II:D:90)
          - 1958 Nov 2-Dec 7 (Box II:D:91)
          - 1959 Jan 11-May 17 (Box II:D:91)
          - 1959 Sep 28 (Box II:D:91)
  - E: Sermon files
    These files are arranged into four parts: 1) Correspondence, 2) Manuscripts, 3) Sermon Proofs, and 4) Index file. Correspondence consists of letters requesting copies of Dr. Peale's sermons as well as comments on them. This is arranged chronologically, then alphabetically by correspondent. Manuscripts are mostly corrected typescripts, but some of the earlier ones are holoscript. These sermons have been distributed to millions of people the world over. They were originally given by Dr. Peale at his various pastorates over the years, such as: University Methodist Church in Syracuse, Kings Highway Methodist church in Brooklyn and the Marble Collegiate Church in New York City. These manuscripts are arranged chronologically by month and year. Sermon proofs contains the galley proofs of sermons given by Dr. Peale at the Marble Collegiate Church. These sermons were published and distributed by Sermon Publications of Pawling, NY. The arrangement of these proofs is chronological. The Index file contains sermon digests, excerpts, notes and illustrations used in Dr. Peale's sermons. This is arranged alphabetically by type of material then chronologically.
    - Correspondence
      - Correspondence, 1944-1947 (Box II:E:1)
      - Correspondence, Sermon Publication Committee, 1948 (Box II:E:1)
      - Correspondence, A-L, 1948 (Box II:E:1)
      - Correspondence, M-Z, 1948 (Box II:E:2)
      - Correspondence, 1949-1950 (Box II:E:2)
      - Correspondence, 1951 (Box II:E:3)
      - Correspondence, A-L, 1952 (Box II:E:3)
      - Correspondence, M-Z, 1952 (Box II:E:4)
      - Correspondence, 1953-1954 (Box II:E:4)
      - Correspondence, 1955, Jan-Mar (Box II:E:5)
      - Correspondence, 1955, Mar-Apr (Box II:E:6)
      - Correspondence, 1955, Apr (Box II:E:7)
      - Correspondence, 1955, Apr-Sep (Box II:E:8)
      - Correspondence, 1955, Sep-Oct (Box II:E:9)
      - Correspondence, 1955, Oct-Dec (Box II:E:10)
      - Correspondence, A-G, 1956 (Box II:E:10)
      - Correspondence, H-N, 1956 (Box II:E:11)
      - Correspondence, O-Ry, 1956 (Box II:E:12)
      - Correspondence, Sa-Ty, 1956 (Box II:E:13)
      - Correspondence, U-Z, 1956 (Box II:E:14)
      - Correspondence, Undated (Box II:E:14)
    - Manuscripts
      - Manuscripts, 1922-1928 (Box II:E:15)
      - Manuscripts, 1933-1936 (Box II:E:15)
      - Manuscripts, 1933-1936 (Box II:E:16)
      - Manuscripts, 1941, May, Sep (Box II:E:16)
      - Manuscripts, 1942, Jan, May-Jul (Box II:E:16)
      - Manuscripts, 1942, Oct-Dec (Box II:E:17)
      - Manuscripts, 1943, Jan-Apr (Box II:E:17)
      - Manuscripts, 1943, May-Jun, Sep (Box II:E:18)
      - Manuscripts, 1946, Feb (Box II:E:18)
      - Manuscripts, Undated (Box II:E:18)
    - Sermon proofs
      - Sermon proofs, 1954; 1956,; 1957 (Box II:E:18)
      - Sermon proofs, 1958; 1959 (Box II:E:19)
      - Sermon proofs, by subject, 1925-1932 (Box II:E:20)
    - Index file
      - Card Index, 1953-1957 (Box II:E:20)
      - Cut Radio Versions, 1942 (Box II:E:20)
      - Sermon Digests, 1953-1954; undated (Box II:E:20)
      - Sermon Discs, 1942 (Box II:E:20)
      - Sermon Excerpts, N.V.P. Special, 1949-1951 (Box II:E:20)
      - Excerpts, Digests, Releases, 1944-1946 (Box II:E:20)
      - Newspaper Releases and Misc. Excerpts (Box II:E:20)
      - Illustrations
        - Illustrations, 1932; 1935-1938 (Box II:E:20)
        - Illustrations, 1938-1946 (Box II:E:21)
        - Illustrations, 1946-1953 (Box II:E:22)
        - Illustrations, 1950-1955 (Box II:E:23)
        - Illustrations, 1955-1956 (Box II:E:24)
        - Illustrations, 1953-1959 (Box II:E:25)
        - Illustrations, Easter, 1959-1960 (Box II:E:26)
      - Sermon material
        - [General], April 12, 1959 (Box II:E:26)
        - Christmas (Box II:E:27)
        - Communion (Box II:E:27)
        - Lincoln (Box II:E:27)
        - Mother's Day (Box II:E:27)
        - New Year's Day (Box II:E:27)
        - Thanksgiving (Box II:E:27)
        - List of Sermons Which have Been Printed (Box II:E:27)
      - Notes and Digests, 1947 (Box II:E:28)
      - Notes, lists and research material, 1922-1932 (Box II:E:28)
      - Outline (Box II:E:28)
      - Procedural material (Box II:E:28)
      - Publication Committee, 1944 (Box II:E:28)
      - Sermon Publication Committee, 1947; 1949 (Box II:E:28)
      - Sermon Publication Committee, 1950-1952 (Box II:E:29)
      - Published copies, 1944; 1951-1954 (Box II:E:29)
      - Published copies, 1955-1956 (Box II:E:30)
      - Stenograph reports, 1940 (Box II:E:30)
      - Tape Recordings of Sermon Given in Washington D.C., 1955 (Box II:E:30)
      - Topics, 1939; 1942-1955 (Box II:E:30)
  - F: Kennedy campaign
    This subseries contains correspondence and published material regarding Dr. Peale's attendance at a conference in Washington in Sept. 1960, held by the Citizens for Religious Freedom, a group consisting of 150 Protestant clergymen and laymen, concerning the election of a Roman Catholic for president. As a result of Dr. Peale's participation in the meeting, a number of people wrote to him, some congratulating him for his stand, others denouncing him. This material is filed in three parts: 1) Correspondence For, contains correspondence, mostly from individuals, but there are many letters from church groups and businesses (arranged chronologically); 2): Correspondence Against, correspondence from the general public, clergymen, church groups and businesses (arranged chronologically); and 3) Published material, including leaflets, newspaper clippings, pamphlets, and periodicals (arranged alphabetically by type).
    - Correspondence for, Aug. 15, 1960-Dec. 22, 1960; Jan. 1, 1961-May 12, 1961;; undated (Box II:F:1-7)
    - Correspondence against, 15 Aug. 10, 1960-Nov. 18, 1960; Jan. 6, 1961-June 14, 1961;; undated (Box II:F:8-15)
    - Correspondence against, 1960-1961
      - Discontinuing Column in Philadelphia Inquirer (Box II:F:16)
      - Kennedy (Box II:F:16)
      - Washington Meeting (Box II:F:16)
      - "What a Protestant Should Do Today" (Box II:F:16)
    - Published material
      - Leaflets (Box II:F:17)
      - Newspaper clippings (Box II:F:17)
      - Newspaper clippings (Box II:F:18)
      - Newspapers (copies) (Box II:F:19)
      - Pamphlets, 1960 (Box II:F:19)
      - Periodicals, 1959; 1960 (Box II:F:19)
  - G: Marble Collegiate Church 100th Anniversary
    This subseries contains correspondence, greetings, a history, mailing lists, minutes and notices pertaining to the 100th Anniversary dinner of the Marble Collegiate Church in New York City. Dr. Peale started his pastorate there in 1932. Also included are pictures, programs, invitations, reservations and related items for this dinner. This material is arranged alphabetically by subject or type.
    - Anniversary Dinner
      - Correspondence Committee (Box II:G:1)
      - Correspondence, general (Box II:G:1)
      - Correspondence, hotel, misc (Box II:G:1)
      - Greetings, special guests (Box II:G:1)
      - History and publicity (Box II:G:1)
      - Mailing lists (Box II:G:1)
      - Minutes, agendas, notices (Box II:G:1)
      - 9/20 Organization Dinner (Box II:G:1)
      - Pictures (Box II:G:1)
      - Programs (Box II:G:2)
      - Programs, invitations, proofs (Box II:G:2)
      - Programs sent list (Box II:G:2)
      - Refunds, donations, complimentary tickets (Box II:G:2)
      - Reservations A-K (Box II:G:2)
      - Reservations, L-Z (Box II:G:3)
      - Seating info (Box II:G:3)
      - Speakers (Box II:G:3)
      - Toastmaster (Box II:G:3)
    - Marble Collegiate Church programs (Box II:G:3)
    - Testimonial dinner (Box II:G:3)
  - H: Research materials
    This subseries contains two parts: 1) General, and 2) Prohibition. General consists of correspondence, printed and published material used by Dr. Peale for research in preparing,sermons, articles and statements. It includes material on subjects such as immorality, marriage problems, retirement, unemployment and teenage problems. It is arranged alphabetically by subject. Prohibition includes news clippings, pamphlets and periodicals, programs, and reports relating to prohibition of drinking intoxicants. There are notes used by Dr. Peale for his speeches and sermons against repeal of the 18th Amendment. This material is arranged alphabetically by type.
    - General
      - Book - Sermons on George Washington, 1932 (Box II:H:1)
      - Christianity and Mental Health, 1955 (Box II:H:1)
      - Correspondence, 1931-1936 (Box II:H:1)
      - How to Be Married and Enjoy It, 1958 (Box II:H:1)
      - Illustrations, 1927 (Box II:H:1)
      - Illustrations for Speaking Engagements, 1948-1950 (Box II:H:1)
      - Immortality, 1954-1955 (Box II:H:1)
      - Integration, 1958-1959 (Box II:H:1)
      - Marriage Problems, 1958 (Box II:H:1)
      - Massanetta Springs Address, 1944-1945 (Box II:H:1)
      - Mental and Physical Conditions, 1958 (Box II:H:1)
      - Perils to Freedom and Spiritual Mobilization, 1946-1948 (Box II:H:1)
      - Perils to Freedom and Spiritual Mobilization, 1946-1948 (Box II:H:2)
      - Religious Problems, 1958 (Box II:H:2)
      - Remarriage - Illegitimate, Illicit Problems, 1958 (Box II:H:2)
      - Requests for School Papers, etc., 1958-1959 (Box II:H:2)
      - Retirement, 1954-1955 (Box II:H:2)
      - The Secret of Abundance, 1958 (Box II:H:2)
      - Spiritual Techniques, 1950-1952 (Box II:H:2)
      - Teen-Age Problems, 1958 (Box II:H:2)
      - Unemployment Relief Committee, 1932 (Box II:H:2)
    - Prohibition
      - Address by Callahan, Patrick Henry, 1927 (Box II:H:2)
      - Annual Address: Colvin D. Leigh, 1932 (Box II:H:2)
      - Book: T.N.T. - It Rocks The Earth, 1932 (Box II:H:2)
      - Bulletins, 1930-1933 (Box II:H:2)
      - Calling Cards (Box II:H:3)
      - Congressional Records, 1931-1933 (Box II:H:3)
      - Leaflets, 1932; undated (Box II:H:3)
      - Membership Cards, 1935-1936 (Box II:H:3)
      - News Clippings, 1932-1933 (Box II:H:3)
      - Newspaper Clippings (Box II:H:4)
      - Notes (Box II:H:4)
      - Pamphlets, 1927-1937 (Box II:H:4)
      - Periodicals, 1930-1954 (Box II:H:5)
      - Play by Ethel Clark, 1935 (Box II:H:5)
      - Programs, 1932-1937 (Box II:H:5)
      - Report, 1933 (Box II:H:5)
      - Reprints of Articles, 1955 (Box II:H:5)
      - Sermons, 1933; undated (Box II:H:5)
      - Speeches, 1930-1933 (Box II:H:5)
  - J: Testimonial Dinner
    This subseries concerns a testimonial dinner which was given in honor of Dr. Peale's twentieth anniversary as pastor of the Marble Collegiate Church on November 18, 1952, at the Hotel Statler. The toastmaster was Lowell Thomas, and among the evening's speakers was J. Edgar Hoover. This subseries includes correspondence, photographs, guest lists, and printed material relating to the social activities involved in the arrangement of this dinner. These materials are arranged alphabetically by subject.
    - Business and Misc. (Box II:J:1)
    - Committee Meeting, Nov.6 1952 (Box II:J:1)
    - Correspondence (Box II:J:1)
    - Dais, regrets (Box II:J:1)
    - Invitation samples (Box II:J:1)
    - Photographs (Box II:J:1)
    - Program (Box II:J:2)
    - Publicity (Box II:J:2)
    - Refunds, Free Tickets, etc. (Box II:J:2)
    - Regrets, etc. (Box II:J:2)
    - Reservations (Box II:J:2)
    - Reservations, A-B (Box II:J:2)
    - Reservations C-R (Box II:J:3)
    - Reservations, S-Z (Box II:J:4)
    - Samples of Materials (Box II:J:4)
    - Tickets not Paid (Box II:J:4)